When I was in the CIA, it used to be my
job. It was my very first job in the CIA
to
to profile foreign leaders for the
president, the vice president, the
national security advisor, and the
secretaries of state and defense.
Anytime they were seeing a world leader,
we had to write a classified
psychological profile of that world
leader.
And I still kind of enjoyed doing it
just for myself.
My job at the agency when I first got
hired was uh to be essentially Saddam
Hussein's classified biographer for the
intelligence community. His His
classified
psychological biographer. And I worked
with a team of psychiatrists,
psychologists, and anthropologists to
make sure that that we had cutting-edge
analysis.
Well, our first profile is going to be
on a man named Reza Pahlavi. Someone who
also attended Lindsey Graham's funeral
yesterday in Washington. Reza Pahlavi is
the former crown prince and the eldest
son of the last Shah of Iran.
He's been waiting in the wings
attempting to jockey to lead Iran in the
event of regime change.
You're going to hear how charismatic he
is in these clips. And you can make your
own decision as to how likely it is that
he's going to be the leader of Iran. But
let me say a couple of things about Reza
Pahlavi.
Um I not so jokingly have referred to
him in podcast appearances in the past
as the clown prince of Iran.
He left Iran as a very young man
in his very early 20s or about the age
of 20 in 1979.
He hasn't been back to Iran since 1979.
He is strongly supported
by Israel,
uh by the Jewish community here in
America,
by the Iranian exile community here in
America, not the entire community, but I
mean like the Southern California very
wealthy uh Iranian exiles.
He lives in a multi-million dollar
palace in Potomac, Maryland, a close in
suburb of Washington, D.C.
But, he's not a player.
He's never been a player.
Since the US and Israel began bombing
Iran, he's appeared on a handful of
podcasts. He was on the Patrick
Bet-David Show
uh once or twice and a couple of other
podcasts
in which he sort of says what you would
expect him to say, that, you know, yes,
the regime is terrible, it has to be
overthrown, the Iranian people have to
be liberated, and then sometimes he'll
say that he's the one who should lead
Iran, and other times he says that he's
not the one who should lead Iran. The
truth is
he would and I've I've said this in the
past and I've gotten death threats for
it. I'm going to say it again. He would
not survive the walk from the plane to
the terminal if he were to go back to
Iran.
Nobody wants him
in Iran. Nobody.
And if there's one thing that the
Israeli and American bombing of Iran
has done
is that it's united the Iranian people.
You can't
You can't attack a country,
murder its religious leader,
murder most of its senior governmental
leadership,
murder all of its military leaders,
murder all of its nuclear scientists,
and say, "We're here to help."
We know we've been bombing you, and we
the first night of the bombing we blew
up the school and killed 160 something
little girls from the school, but but
we're the good guys and we're here to
help you. And we want to take this
stooge, this clown from Potomac,
Maryland and impose him on you so that
he can be a dictator like his father
was.
Well, the reason that that Reza
Pahlavi's father
Mohammad Reza Pahlavi was overthrown in
the first place is because he was a
bloodthirsty, murderous dictator.
And people were tired
of being murdered
by the SAVAK, the secret police.
So, Reza Pahlavi's not going back to
Iran. He's not going to lead Iran. He's
not going to be a player in any
respect.
Although
the pro-war faction of the Republican
Party
and the Israeli government think he's
great.
We've got a little clip that we want to
show you of an interview that Reza
Pahlavi did yesterday with Reuters.
>> There've been reports and they're kind
of anonymous that you've received
funding from Israel and Saudi Arabia. Is
that true?
>> Absolutely false. I have not been a
recipient of any governmental or public
fund on the outside.
Every dime that comes to my campaign
comes from private donations of
supporters. Hopefully, we'll have more
benefactors that give us bigger checks.
>> From where we're sitting today, when do
you think regime change might occur?
>> I think we're very close to it and the
reason I say this is because first and
foremost, the regime is at its weakest
it's ever been since 47 years.
Not to mention the fact that in terms of
legitimacy, it has totally lost any
remaining possible legitimacy it might
have had.
>> That's just wrong.
He's just wrong.
He forgets that when his father was
first overthrown, Iran went through a
series of presidents. There was even an
editorial cartoon at the time, I
remember, in the New York Times, where
Ayatollah Khomeini was telling some
Iranian-looking guy, "I have good news
and I have bad news. The good news is
I'm naming you president of Iran. The
bad news is I'm naming you president of
Iran."
Because there was a cycle of presidents
of Iran that would just get blown up or
shot or arrested or disappeared or
whatever.
That was when the regime was weak.
Not today.
This war has forced
the Iranian populace together, to rally.
You know, you would think that we would
have learned a lesson
with the Iraq war.
We have so convinced ourselves that
we're the good guys, we just can't
fathom the notion that when we cross a
border, we're not going to be seen as
liberators. We're going to be seen as
invaders and occupiers. It happens time
and time again. We couldn't defeat the
Taliban. They didn't even have shoes.
And they beat us.
We couldn't defeat the Iraqis. Iraq is
still in a state of chaos.
But we think that we're going to be
greeted in as liberators in Iran?
Why would we think that?
We would think that because people don't
have any understanding of history.
So, here is this clown waiting in the
wings, pretending to jockey to lead Iran
in the event of regime change.
Well, I would liken him to Ahmed
Chalabi.
For those of you who don't remember
Ahmed Chalabi, he was a similar clown
that was in the pay of the CIA, the
American government, and we made this
really stupid plan to make him the
president of Iraq as soon as we
overthrew Saddam Hussein and the Iraqi
people said, "Oh, no, you don't."
Well, it's happening again.